A splendid time is guaranteed for all!
Sgt. Pepper's Lonely Hearts Club Band is a adventure,
music, comedy film directed by Michael Schultz.
A small town band makes it big, but loses track of their roots, as they get
caught up into the big-time machinations of the music biz.
Now, they must thwart a plot to destroy their home town.
Built around the music of The Beatles, this musical uses some big
name groups like Peter Frampton and Aerosmith.
Billy Shears, played by Peter Frampton.
Mark Henderson, played by Barry Gibb.
Dave Henderson, played by Robin Gibb.
Bob Henderson, played by Maurice Gibb.
Mean Mr. Mustard, played by Frankie Howerd.
Dougie Shears, played by Paul Nicholas.
Pepper's Lonely Hearts Club Band is a 1978 American jukebox musical comedy film directed by Michael Schultz,
written by Henry Edwards and starring an ensemble cast led by Peter Frampton and the Bee Gees.
Depicting the loosely constructed story of a band as they wrangle with the music industry and battle evil forces bent on stealing their instruments and corrupting
their hometown of Heartland, the film is presented in a form similar to that of a rock opera, with the songs providing "dialogue" to carry the story.
George Burns has most of the spoken lines that act to
clarify the plot and provide further narration.
The film's soundtrack, released as an accompanying double album, features new
versions of songs originally written and performed by the Beatles.
The film draws primarily from two of the band's albums, 1967's Sgt.
Pepper's Lonely Hearts Club Band and 1969's Abbey Road, with
additional selections from other Beatles albums.
The production was loosely adapted from Sgt.
Pepper's Lonely Hearts Club Band on the Road, a 1974
off-Broadway production directed by Tom O'Horgan.
The film was met with minor box office success, grossing $20.4 million against a budget of $13 million, but overwhelmingly
negative reviews from critics for its weak plot and poor acting as well as its musical interpretations.
However, some of the musical numbers, particularly Earth, Wind & Fire's cover of "Got to Get You Into My Life" and Aerosmith's cover of "Come
Together", were met with high praise, the former earning Earth, Wind & Fire a Grammy, and the latter being a top-25 hit single.
The film explores themes of bus, convertible, record producer, robot, theft.
The tone is lighthearted and thought_provoking.